ukutabs.com 2018-08-15

# Privacy Policy • UkuWorld

Privacy matters a lot to me, but it can be confusing as well. On this page I try to explain my approach to privacy on all the UkuWorld network websites (i.e. [UkuChords.com](https://ukuchords.com/), [UkuGuides.com](https://ukuguides.com/), [UkuNotes.com](https://ukunotes.com/), [UkuScales.com](https://ukuscales.com/), [UkuTabs.com](https://ukutabs.com/), [UkuTuner.com](https://ukutuner.com/), [UkuWorld.com](https://ukuworld.com/) and any derived website name ) and how it affects you, as a user. **Disclaimer: all data is collected anonymously and will never be shared with third parties!**

## Short Version

Statistics are collected anonymously about your visit. For example: which of UkuTabs’ songs you’ve viewed. Social services such as Facebook, twitter, YouTube and Google+ are known to track your steps carefully if you use their services, by using their code (e.g. sharing buttons) implemented on sites. On none of the UkuWorld websites I have implemented such code, so rest assured that you are not being tracked by these services.

I take great care to keep your information safe if you register an account on UkuTabs or UkuWorld. I will never share the information of your account (such as your email address) with third parties. Your information is stored safely on a secure server behind a firewall and all connections to the UkuWorld websites and servers use secure SSL protection with A+ rating. You can visit any of the following links to verify this rating using an independent SSL rater:

• [A+ SSL security rating for UkuChords.com](https://www.ssllabs.com/ssltest/analyze.html?d=ukuchords.com&latest)  
• [A+ SSL security rating for UkuGuides.com](https://www.ssllabs.com/ssltest/analyze.html?d=ukuguides.com&latest)  
• [A+ SSL security rating for UkuScales.com](https://www.ssllabs.com/ssltest/analyze.html?d=ukuscales.com&latest)  
• [A+ SSL security rating for UkuTabs.com](https://www.ssllabs.com/ssltest/analyze.html?d=ukutabs.com&latest)  
• [A+ SSL security rating for UkuTuner.com](https://www.ssllabs.com/ssltest/analyze.html?d=ukutuner.com&latest)  
• [A+ SSL security rating for UkuWorld.com](https://www.ssllabs.com/ssltest/analyze.html?d=ukuworld.com&latest)

These are just the key points. If you want to know more details about how and which statistics are collected, feel free to keep on reading.

## Measuring Visitors

I measure visitors to the UkuWorld websites using the very popular and secure Google Analytics (referred to as GA). GA anonymously records what pages you view within the UkuWorld network, how you arrived at the webpage and some basic information about your computer. I can’t stress enough that all that information is anonymous – so I will never know who you are; I will just see that _somebody visited_ a webpage within the UkuWorld network.

The information I collect from these analytics helps me understand what parts of the UkuWorld network are doing well, how people arrive at a specific webpage and so on. Like most websites, I genuinely use this information to make the UkuWorld network and the associated websites better as it allows me to discover errors or faulty pages within the network.

If you want to learn more about Google Analytics and how it works, you can read [this detailed WikiPedia page](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Google_Analytics) if you wish.

## Facebook, Twitter and other social networks

These services provide code which can be embedded onto websites. This code mainly provides social (sharing) buttons and similar features such as the “Like” and “Tweet” buttons. This allows these services to track your ‘digital’ steps and follow where you go. Because I, as a web developer, have no control at all over these services and their privacy policy and choose to not use services like this. I do provide links to those social networks, for example to the UkuWorld twitter account, but I do not use code provided by them.

## If you sign up on UkuTabs or UkuWorld

All services on UkuTabs or other UkuWorld websites are 100% free of charge. When you sign up for an account on UkuTabs or UkuWorld I only ask for your email address. The username can be anything you want. An email address is however a necessity to properly create an account and for example restore your password. Once again, I will never share this information of your account with third parties. When you favorite a song, it is recored that your account (for which I only have a username and email address) favorited that specific song. This information is only viewable by the administrator, me, and never shared with anybody else. The only way that I use the information about you favoriting a specific song, is to construct the [99 Top Tabs by Favorites](https://ukutabs.com/top-tabs/top-tabs-by-favorites/). Your information is never linked, shown or shared.

## Security

Here at UkuWorld I take many precautions to prevent the loss, misuse or alteration of your personal information. These precautions include (but are not limited to):

• Use of strict full SSL encryption (HTTPS) for every connection to the server or websites. You can check the security rating of every website within the UkuWorld network by clicking the links above.  
• The server hardware is stored in secured datacentres and I’ve configured the firewalls of the servers myself to make them as strict as possible.  
• All access to information is restricted by password and/or secure keys.  
• Restrictions to what information can be accessed via any location.

Whilst I take great care to ensure that any confidential information remains protected, I cannot guarantee the security of data sent over the Internet. It is for example possible that your computer is infected with malware or that the server gets hacked by experienced hackers. In almost five years there hasn’t been one issue and I’ll do my very best to keep it this way.

You are of course responsible for keeping your password and user details confidential. Nobody at UkuWorld will ever ask you for your password, so please don’t trust anybody asking you for it!

## Updates to this policy

I reserve the right to update this privacy policy from time-to-time, particularly as technology changes, without giving notice. You can always check this page for the latest version.

## Advertisements

In order to properly display advertisements third party cookies are used.

## Questions?

If you have any questions about this privacy policy, your personal data or something else, feel free to send me an email at [privacy [at] ukuworld.com](mailto:privacy@ukuworld.com) or use the [contact form](https://ukuworld.com/contact/).
